Alessandro R. Galloni

329 Montgomery Street, Highland Park, NJ 08904, USA

□ (+1) 332-201-5325 | ■ alessandro.qalloni.11@ucl.ac.uk | □ argalloni | ▶ @argalloni | Nationality: USA, Italy (dual citizenship)

Summary _____

Self-motivated and collaborative computational neuroscientist, using machine learning and AI tools to explore biologically plausible learning algorithms in the brain. With a background in systems neuroscience, I have over 8 years of research experience managing both computational and experimental research projects. Specialties include deep learning in PyTorch (particularly computer vision), building exploratory data analysis pipelines, computational modeling, scientific communication, and data visualization.

Research Experience _____

Rutgers University, Center for Advanced Biotechnology and Medicine

Piscataway (NJ), USA

COMPUTATIONAL NEUROSCIENTIST (EMBO POSTDOCTORAL FELLOW)

Feb. 2021 - present

Experience building and analyzing custom neural networks trained on computer vision and reinforcement learning tasks

- Built a **PyTorch wrapper** for biology-inspired neural networks
- · Led a collaboration on neuromorphic computing, developing neuroAI models for reinforcement learning on novel hardware
- Built recurrent neural networks to model neural dynamics in the brain
- Used Principal Component Analysis (PCA) to visualize high-dimensional loss landscapes during neural network learning
- · Developed analysis pipeline for fitting GLM models and visualizing experimental neural data recorded from the hippocampus of mice

The Francis Crick Institute / University College London

London, UK

PHD IN NEUROSCIENCE Sept. 2015 - Feb. 2021

Performing neuroscience experiments (in mice) and running detailed simulations of neuronal biophysics

- Used Python and MATLAB to analyze connectivity and activation properties in neurons across different visual areas of the mouse brain
- · Created detailed biophysical models to simulate the influence of dendrites on neuronal activation
- Designed and executed experiments, publishing 2 first-author papers

University College London

London, UK

MSci Thesis Research Oct. 2014 - March 2015

- · Built Arduino-based hardware with custom 3D-printed parts to study sleep patterns in zebrafish
- · Analyzed time series of their behavioral data

Education

University College London & The Francis Crick Institute

London, UK

PHD IN NEUROSCIENCE (BOEHRINGER INGELHEIM FONDS FELLOW)

2015 - 2020

• Awarded competitive Boehringer Ingelheim Fonds fellowship

University College London

London, UK

MASTER OF SCIENCE (MSCI) IN NEUROSCIENCE (INTEGRATED UNDERGRADUATE AND MASTER'S DEGREE)

2011 - 2015

• Grade: First Class (Hons.) (highest grade in the UK system)

Skills

TECHNICAL **Software engineering** Deep learning (PyTorch), scientific computing (NumPy, SciPy), jupyter, pandas, matplotlib, git

Programming Languages Python, MatLab, Igor Pro

Imaging Confocal microscopy, slide scanner fluorescence imaging

Other Software Adobe Illustrator, LaTeX

Electrophysiology Patch-clamp voltage recordings from live mouse neurons

LANGUAGES English native level

Italian native level

Swedish native level speaking, intermediate level writing/reading

French Intermediate (B1-B2 level)

Additional Iraining	
Neuromatch Academy – Deep Learning (NMA-DL)	New York, USA
3-week course on deep learning using modern neural network architectures	2021
CAJAL Course in Computational Neuroscience	Lisbon, Portugal
4-week course in computational neuroscience at the Champalimaud Centre for the Unknown	2018
Science communication course (Boehringer Ingelheim Fonds)	Mainz, Germany
Training on scientific presentation to both technical and lay audiences, data visualization and figure design	2017
EMBO Laboratory Leadership course	New York, USA

2024

Leadership & Management Experience

Course covering effective approaches to leadership and communication when building and managing teams

Leadership & Management Experience	
Workshop organizer at COSYNE 2023	Cold Spring Harbor, USA
Co-organized a workshop on biological learning rules at the Computational & Systems Neuroscience conference	March 2023
Teaching at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory	Cold Spring Harbor, USA
Taught hands-on practical component of brain slice physiology with patch-clamp recordings in the intensive 3-week summer school on Ion Channels in Synaptic and Neural Circuit Physiology	June 2023
Supervising graduate and undergraduate students at Rutgers University	Piscataway (NJ), USA
Supervised summer research projects for 6 undergraduate students. Currently co-supervising one PhD student on a project spanning both experimental and computational techniques	2021 - 2024
Teaching assistant at University College London	London, UK
Supervised undergraduate laboratory practicals in neurophysiology and histology	2016 - 2019

Honors & Awards

۸ ما ما:۱: ۵ مه ما Two:۱۰۰ م

Competitive awards		Minor awards	
2022 EMBO Postdoctoral Fellowship (v	value: \$125'000)	2023 Best presentation (1st place), Rutgers Postdoctoral Symposiu	ım
2016 Boehringer Ingelheim Fonds PhD	Fellowship (value: \$110'000)	2017 Poster prize (2nd place), Cortical Feedback spring workshop	
2013 UCL Dean's List award for outstan	nding academic achievements	2013 UCL Dean's Summer Scholarship (8 week research project)	
2012 UCL Dean's List award for outstar	nding academic achievements	2012 Wellcome Trust Biomedical Scholarship (8 week research proj	ject)

Publications

Neuromorphic one-shot learning utilizing a phase-transition material

Galloni, A.R., Yuan, Y., et al., Ramanathan, S., Milstein, A.D., Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS) USA, 121(17)

- Computational neuroscience / Machine Learning: Reinforcement learning on neuromorphic hardware
- 2022 Recurrent excitatory feedback from mossy cells enhances sparsity and pattern separation in the dentate gyrus
 Galloni, A.R., Samadzelkava, A., Hiremath, K., Oumnov, R., Milstein, A.D., Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience, 16:82
 - Computational Neuroscience: Neural dynamics in biologically realistic excitatory/inhibitory recurrent networks
- Dendritic domain-specific sampling of long-range axons shapes feedforward and feedback connectivity of L5 neurons Galloni, A.R., Ye, Z., Rancz, E.A., Journal of Neuroscience, 42(16) 3394-3405
 - Neurophysiology / Signal Processing: Spatio-temporal distributions of synaptic activity underlying long-range neural connections
- Apical length governs computational diversity of layer 5 pyramidal neurons Galloni, A.R., Laffere, A., Rancz, E.A., eLife, e55761
 - Neurophysiology / Computational Neuroscience: Impact of dendritic morphology on electrical properties of neurons
 - Selected for poster presentation at the 2018 Computational & Systems Neuroscience (COSYNE) conference